<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Biology Reproducibility Project</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Biology Reproducibility Project</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Copyright 2018 Jeffrey A. Walker</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Data from: Feeding ecology is the primary driver of beak shape diversification in waterfowl</title>
      <link>/post/data-from-feeding-ecology-is-the-primary-driver-of-beak-shape-diversification-in-waterfowl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/data-from-feeding-ecology-is-the-primary-driver-of-beak-shape-diversification-in-waterfowl/</guid>
      <description>Source  Reproducibility  Cool morphometrics blah blah blah blah blah blah blah
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data from: Density triggers maternal hormones that increase adaptive offspring growth in a wild mammal</title>
      <link>/post/data-from-density-triggers-maternal-hormones-that-increase-adaptive-offspring-growth-in-a-wild-mammal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/data-from-density-triggers-maternal-hormones-that-increase-adaptive-offspring-growth-in-a-wild-mammal/</guid>
      <description>Sources Background Reproducibility Effect of spruce cone availability on local density (Fig. 1B)  Effect of Density on growth rate (Fig. 2/Table S2) Reproducibility Red flags Growth rate is a change score and is confounding by the basline Figure 2 doesn’t make sense   Effect of Density on fecal cortisol metabolites (Fig. 3/Table S4) Reproducibility Red flags one-tailed tests Forking paths Confounding Density and Treatment in Fig 3A,B/Table S4 What is effect of ignoring Chickadee manipulation in Fig 3C/Table S4 Justification for using chickadee playback as “Control” Summary of Red Flags for Figure 3/Table S4   Effect of FCM on offspring growth rate (Table S5) Reproducibility Explore Red flags small effect in obersvational design Table S5 CIs How is FCM “corrected?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>