<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on The Biology Reproducibility Project</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on The Biology Reproducibility Project</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Copyright 2018 Jeffrey A. Walker</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Data from: Response of bluebunch wheatgrass to invasion differences in competitive ability among invader-experienced and naïve populations</title>
      <link>/post/data-from-response-of-bluebunch-wheatgrass-to-invasion-differences-in-competitive-ability-among-invader-experienced-and-na%C3%AFve-populations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/data-from-response-of-bluebunch-wheatgrass-to-invasion-differences-in-competitive-ability-among-invader-experienced-and-na%C3%AFve-populations/</guid>
      <description>Sources Summary Caveats Setup Import Reproducibility Table 1 Methods Check on balance The model is unclear Table 1–published Table 1 - repro  Figure 1 Fig 1 – published Fig 1 – repro  3.1.1 Seedling 3.1.2 Juvenile 3.2 Relative Interaction Index Supression  Fig 2 Fig 2 – published Fig 2 repro   Statistical red flags   Sources Gibson A, Nelson CR, Atwater DZ (2018) Response of bluebunch wheatgrass to invasion: Differences in competitive ability among invader-experienced and invader-naïve populations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data from: Herbivory and eutrophication mediate grassland plant nutrient responses across a global climatic gradient</title>
      <link>/post/data-from-herbivory-and-eutrophication-mediate-grassland-plant-nutrient-responses-across-a-global-climatic-gradient/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/data-from-herbivory-and-eutrophication-mediate-grassland-plant-nutrient-responses-across-a-global-climatic-gradient/</guid>
      <description>Sources Summary Caveats Setup Import Reproducibility Statistical red flags   Sources Anderson TM, Griffith DM, Grace JB, Lind EM, Adler PB, Biederman LA, Blumenthal DM, Daleo P, Firn J, Hagenah N, Harpole WS, MacDougall AS, McCulley RL, Prober SM, Risch AC, Sankaran M, Schütz M, Seabloom EW, Stevens CJ, Sullivan LL, Wragg PD, Borer ET (2018) Herbivory and eutrophication mediate grassland plant nutrient responses across a global climatic gradient.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data from: Perceived threats of infanticide reduce maternal allocation during lactation and lead to elevated oxidative damage in offspring</title>
      <link>/post/data-from-perceived-threats-of-infanticide-reduce-maternal-allocation-during-lactation-and-lead-to-elevated-oxidative-damage-in-offspring/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/data-from-perceived-threats-of-infanticide-reduce-maternal-allocation-during-lactation-and-lead-to-elevated-oxidative-damage-in-offspring/</guid>
      <description>Sources Summary Caveats Setup Import Reproducibility Offspring weight Maternal behaviour Glucocorticoid metabolites in mothers Fig. 3 Oxidative stress in offspring  Statistical Red Flags 1. Computation of ANOVA table using Afex package How balanced is the design ANOVA using Afex (computation above)  3 ANOVA table using lme/lmer Compare LMM to ANOVA table using lm() and AOV (ignoring clustering due to repeated measures) Plot it to visualize the effects     Sources Gale T, Garratt M, Brooks RC (2018) Perceived threats of infanticide reduce maternal allocation during lactation and lead to elevated oxidative damage in offspring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data from: Habitat management alters thermal opportunity</title>
      <link>/post/data-from-habitat-management-alters-thermal-opportunity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/data-from-habitat-management-alters-thermal-opportunity/</guid>
      <description>Sources Summary Caveats Setup Import Cleaning Reproducibility Selected temperatures and thermal quality of habitat Thermal preference (Tset) Thermal quality of habitat (de) Table 1 Encounter rates Fig 2  Lizard body temperatures and extent of thermoregulation Thermal performance curves and critical thermal limits  Statistical Red Flags Best practice recommendations   Sources Neel LK, McBrayer LD (2018) Habitat management alters thermal opportunity. Functional Ecology 32(8): 2029-2039. https://doi.org/10.1111/1365-2435.13123</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data from: The significance of prey avoidance behaviour for the maintenance of a predator colour polymorphism</title>
      <link>/post/data-from-the-significance-of-prey-avoidance-behaviour-for-the-maintenance-of-a-predator-colour-polymorphism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/data-from-the-significance-of-prey-avoidance-behaviour-for-the-maintenance-of-a-predator-colour-polymorphism/</guid>
      <description>Sources Summary Caveats Setup Import Reproducibility Experiment 1 Statistical methods cleaning and recoding Table 1 reported table 1 Effect of spider treatments Figure 1  Experiment 2 Statistical Methods Offer 1 – nonparametric 2-way ANOVA Figure 2 Offer 2   Statistical Red Flags   Sources Ajuria Ibarra H, Kinahan M, Marcetteau J, Mehigan AJR, Ziegelmeier RO, Reader T (2018) The significance of prey avoidance behaviour for the maintenance of a predator colour polymorphism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data from Organic matter and nutrient inputs from large wildlife influence ecosystem function in the Mara River, Africa</title>
      <link>/post/data-from-organic-matter-and-nutrient-inputs-from-large-wildlife-influence-ecosystem-function-in-the-mara-river-africa/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/data-from-organic-matter-and-nutrient-inputs-from-large-wildlife-influence-ecosystem-function-in-the-mara-river-africa/</guid>
      <description>Sources Summary Caveats Set up Import Reproducibility Nutrient dissolution rates Statistical methods ANOVA results Posthoc pairwise comparisons  Decomposition rates Statistical methods ANOVA results  Nutrient limitation Statistical method Respiration Results Chlorophyll a results  Ecosystem Function Experimental Streams River Biofilms    Statistical red-flags   Sources Subalusky AL, Dutton CL, Njoroge L, Rosi EJ, Post DM (2018) Organic matter and nutrient inputs from large wildlife influence ecosystem function in the Mara River, Africa.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data from: Density-dependent positive feedbacks buffer aquatic plants from interactive effects of eutrophication and predator loss</title>
      <link>/post/data-from-density-dependent-positive-feedbacks-buffer-aquatic-plants-from-interactive-effects-of-eutrophication-and-predator-loss/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/data-from-density-dependent-positive-feedbacks-buffer-aquatic-plants-from-interactive-effects-of-eutrophication-and-predator-loss/</guid>
      <description>Sources Summary Caveats Set up Import data cleaning  Reproducibility Appendix S5 Table S1 reproducing epiphytic algae biomass columns  in-text Appendix S5 Table S2 Figure 2  Statistical Red-flags Figure red-flags  Simulate this   Sources Source: Donadi S, Austin ÅN, Svartgren E, Eriksson BK, Hansen JP, Eklöf JS (2018) Density-dependent positive feedbacks buffer aquatic plants from interactive effects of eutrophication and predator loss. Ecology 99(11): 2515-2524.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data from: Litter removal in a tropical rain forest reduces fine root biomass and production but litter addition has few effects</title>
      <link>/post/data-from-litter-removal-in-a-tropical-rain-forest-reduces-fine-root-biomass-and-production-but-litter-addition-has-few-effects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/data-from-litter-removal-in-a-tropical-rain-forest-reduces-fine-root-biomass-and-production-but-litter-addition-has-few-effects/</guid>
      <description>Sources Summary Caveats Set up Functions  import Note in file Data inconsistencies Data pre-processing  Reproducibility Section: Fine root mass and production My ANOVA results reported ANOVA results Did the authors use a one way ANOVA with no random effects? Figure 1 post-hoc tests for fig 1 Fine root mass production effects of treatment on FRB and FRB production figure 2  Section: Fine root length: standing crop, production and survivorship table 1 Figure 3 post hoc tests for fig.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data from: Interactions among predators and plant specificity protects herbivores from top predators</title>
      <link>/post/data-from-interactions-among-predators-and-plant-specificity-protects-herbivores-from-top-predators/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/data-from-interactions-among-predators-and-plant-specificity-protects-herbivores-from-top-predators/</guid>
      <description>Summary Caveats Set up Import Reproducibility Effect on total predators my results reported results  Effect on total herbaceous my results reported results  ANOVA table in Appendix 3, Table S1 Fig 1 Subsetting the response spiders predatory insects Hemiptera Coleoptera Lepidoptera Orthoptera  Fig S6  Statistical red-flags   Source: Bosc C, Roets F, Hui C, Pauw A (2018) Interactions among predators and plant specificity protect herbivores from top predators.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data from: Frequency of virus-resistant hosts determines experimental community dynamics</title>
      <link>/post/data-from-frequency-of-virus-resistant-hosts-determines-experimental-community-dynamics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/data-from-frequency-of-virus-resistant-hosts-determines-experimental-community-dynamics/</guid>
      <description>Summary Caveats Set up Reproducibility missing data Table 1 what model? AOV vs. lmer AOV computation Table 1 – my results Table 1 – reported results Did the authors throw out A3 for Chlorella and Rotifer?  Table 2 AOV v lmer Table 2 – my results Table 2 – reported Did the authors throw out A3 for Chlorella and Rotifer?  Figure 2  Statistical presentation   Source: Coloma S, Gaedke U, Sivonen K, Hiltunen T (2018) Frequency of virus-resistant hosts determines experimental community dynamics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data from Critical thermal limits affected differently by developmental and adult thermal fluctuations</title>
      <link>/post/data-from-critical-thermal-limits-affected-differently-by-developmental-and-adult-thermal-fluctuations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/data-from-critical-thermal-limits-affected-differently-by-developmental-and-adult-thermal-fluctuations/</guid>
      <description>Sources Background Reproducibility key Caveats  Reproducibility Table 1 (Results of ANOVA for effects on CTmin and CTmax of ±4 and ±8°C amplitude fluctuation after developmental acclimation (Fig. 2A)) Table 2 results Table 3 results  Post-publication review   Sources Salachan PV, Sørensen JG (2017) Critical thermal limits affected differently by developmental and adult thermal fluctuations. Journal of Experimental Biology 220(23): 4471-4478. https://doi.org/10.1242/jeb.165308
Salachan PV, Sørensen JG (2017) Data from: Critical thermal limits affected differently by developmental and adult thermal fluctuations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data from The interaction between predation risk and food ration on behavior and morphology of Eurasian perch</title>
      <link>/post/data-from-the-interaction-between-predation-risk-and-food-ration-on-behavior-and-morphology-of-eurasian-perch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/data-from-the-interaction-between-predation-risk-and-food-ration-on-behavior-and-morphology-of-eurasian-perch/</guid>
      <description>Sources Background Reproducibility key Caveats  Reproducibility Figure 1/Table 1 (Condition and Length) Condition index Table 1 Tukey Contrasts  Figure 2/Table 2 (Behavior) Table 2  Morphometrics  Post-publication review   Sources Svanbäck R, Zha Y, Brönmark C, Johansson F (2017) The interaction between predation risk and food ration on behavior and morphology of Eurasian perch. Ecology and Evolution 7(20): 8567-8577. https://doi.org/10.1002/ece3.3330
Svanback R, Zha Y, Brönmark C, Johansson F (2017) Data from: The interaction between predation risk and food ration on behavior and morphology of Eurasian perch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data from Ontogenetic thermal tolerance and performance of ectotherms at variable temperatures</title>
      <link>/post/data-from-ontogenetic-thermal-tolerance-and-performance-of-ectotherms-at-variable-temperatures/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/data-from-ontogenetic-thermal-tolerance-and-performance-of-ectotherms-at-variable-temperatures/</guid>
      <description>Sources Background Reproducibility key Caveats  Summary of Re-analysis Reproducibility Post-publication review  Reproducibility Table 1 Table 2 Table 3 Figure 2  Post-publication review Use the full model to compare to Huey &amp;amp; Kinsolver Table of contrasts needed for interpretation Harrell Plots of full model ignoring sex Summary of my Harrell Plots and Table of contrasts  Shift in UTL  Red Flags Statistical misconceptions   Sources Cavieres G, Bogdanovich JM, Bozinovic F (2016) Ontogenetic thermal tolerance and performance of ectotherms at variable temperatures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data from: Success despite the stress -- violet-green swallows increase glucocorticoids and maintain reproductive output despite experimental increases in flight costs</title>
      <link>/post/data-from-success-despite-the-stress-violet-green-swallows-increase-glucocorticoids-and-maintain-reproductive-output-despite-experimental-increases-in-flight-costs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/data-from-success-despite-the-stress-violet-green-swallows-increase-glucocorticoids-and-maintain-reproductive-output-despite-experimental-increases-in-flight-costs/</guid>
      <description>Sources Background Reproducibility key Caveats  Data Reproducibility Initial measures Change in Cort Change in Body Mass  Post-publication review “no significant differences” among treatment groups at baseline does not protect in any way against the bias in change scores (post - pre treatment measure) Estimates of treatment effects on Cortisol and Mass were not adjusted for baseline values Simulation to explore behavior in lmm vs. ANCOVA-lm vs. cLDA Adjustment for baseline comparing \(Cort_b\)    Sources Rivers JW, Newberry GN, Schwarz CJ, Ardia DR (2017) Success despite the stress: violet-green swallows increase glucocorticoids and maintain reproductive output despite experimental increases in flight costs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data from: Density triggers maternal hormones that increase adaptive offspring growth in a wild mammal</title>
      <link>/post/data-from-density-triggers-maternal-hormones-that-increase-adaptive-offspring-growth-in-a-wild-mammal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/data-from-density-triggers-maternal-hormones-that-increase-adaptive-offspring-growth-in-a-wild-mammal/</guid>
      <description>Sources Background Reproducibility key Caveats  Reproducibility Effect of spruce cone availability on local density (Fig. 1B) Effect of Density on growth rate (Fig. 2/Table S2) Effect of Density on fecal cortisol metabolites (Fig. 3/Table S4) Effect of FCM on offspring growth rate (Table S5) Effect of experiment Cortisol on growth rate (Table S6)  Red flags Effect of Density on growth rate (Fig. 2/Table S2) Growth rate is a change score and is confounded by the basline Figure 2 doesn’t make sense  Effect of Density on fecal cortisol metabolites (Fig.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>