<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on The Biology Reproducibility Project</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on The Biology Reproducibility Project</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Copyright 2018 Jeffrey A. Walker</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Data from Ontogenetic thermal tolerance and performance of ectotherms at variable temperatures</title>
      <link>/post/data-from-ontogenetic-thermal-tolerance-and-performance-of-ectotherms-at-variable-temperatures/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/data-from-ontogenetic-thermal-tolerance-and-performance-of-ectotherms-at-variable-temperatures/</guid>
      <description>Sources Background Summary of Re-analysis Reproducibility Post-publication review  Reproducibility Table 1 Table 2 Table 3 Figure 2  Post-publication review Use the full model to compare to Huey &amp;amp; Kinsolver Table of contrasts needed for interpretation Harrell Plots of full model ignoring sex Summary of my Harrell Plots and Table of contrasts  Shift in UTL  Red Flags Statistical misconceptions   Sources Cavieres G, Bogdanovich JM, Bozinovic F (2016) Ontogenetic thermal tolerance and performance of ectotherms at variable temperatures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data from: Success despite the stress -- violet-green swallows increase glucocorticoids and maintain reproductive output despite experimental increases in flight costs</title>
      <link>/post/data-from-success-despite-the-stress-violet-green-swallows-increase-glucocorticoids-and-maintain-reproductive-output-despite-experimental-increases-in-flight-costs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/data-from-success-despite-the-stress-violet-green-swallows-increase-glucocorticoids-and-maintain-reproductive-output-despite-experimental-increases-in-flight-costs/</guid>
      <description>Sources Background Data Reproducibility Reproducibility key Initial measures Change in Cort Change in Body Mass  Post-publication review “no significant differences” among treatment groups at baseline does not protect in any way against the bias in change scores (post - pre treatment measure) Estimates of treatment effects on Cortisol and Mass were not adjusted for baseline values Simulation to explore behavior in lmm vs. ANCOVA-lm vs. cLDA Adjustment for baseline comparing \(Cort_b\)    Sources Rivers JW, Newberry GN, Schwarz CJ, Ardia DR (2017) Success despite the stress: violet-green swallows increase glucocorticoids and maintain reproductive output despite experimental increases in flight costs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data from: Density triggers maternal hormones that increase adaptive offspring growth in a wild mammal</title>
      <link>/post/data-from-density-triggers-maternal-hormones-that-increase-adaptive-offspring-growth-in-a-wild-mammal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/data-from-density-triggers-maternal-hormones-that-increase-adaptive-offspring-growth-in-a-wild-mammal/</guid>
      <description>Sources Background Reproducibility Effect of spruce cone availability on local density (Fig. 1B) Effect of Density on growth rate (Fig. 2/Table S2) Effect of Density on fecal cortisol metabolites (Fig. 3/Table S4) Effect of FCM on offspring growth rate (Table S5) Effect of experiment Cortisol on growth rate (Table S6)  Red flags Effect of Density on growth rate (Fig. 2/Table S2) Growth rate is a change score and is confounding by the basline Figure 2 doesn’t make sense  Effect of Density on fecal cortisol metabolites (Fig.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>