<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2x2 on The Biology Reproducibility Project</title>
    <link>/tags/2x2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2x2 on The Biology Reproducibility Project</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Copyright 2018 Jeffrey A. Walker</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/2x2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Data from Critical thermal limits affected differently by developmental and adult thermal fluctuations</title>
      <link>/post/data-from-critical-thermal-limits-affected-differently-by-developmental-and-adult-thermal-fluctuations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/data-from-critical-thermal-limits-affected-differently-by-developmental-and-adult-thermal-fluctuations/</guid>
      <description>Sources Background Reproducibility Reproducibility key Table 1 (Results of ANOVA for effects on CTmin and CTmax of ±4 and ±8°C amplitude fluctuation after developmental acclimation (Fig. 2A)) Table 2 results Table 3 results  Post-publication review   Sources Salachan PV, Sørensen JG (2017) Critical thermal limits affected differently by developmental and adult thermal fluctuations. Journal of Experimental Biology 220(23): 4471-4478. https://doi.org/10.1242/jeb.165308
Salachan PV, Sørensen JG (2017) Data from: Critical thermal limits affected differently by developmental and adult thermal fluctuations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data from Ontogenetic thermal tolerance and performance of ectotherms at variable temperatures</title>
      <link>/post/data-from-ontogenetic-thermal-tolerance-and-performance-of-ectotherms-at-variable-temperatures/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/data-from-ontogenetic-thermal-tolerance-and-performance-of-ectotherms-at-variable-temperatures/</guid>
      <description>Sources Background Summary of Re-analysis Reproducibility Post-publication review  Reproducibility Table 1 Table 2 Table 3 Figure 2  Post-publication review Use the full model to compare to Huey &amp;amp; Kinsolver Table of contrasts needed for interpretation Harrell Plots of full model ignoring sex Summary of my Harrell Plots and Table of contrasts  Shift in UTL  Red Flags Statistical misconceptions   Sources Cavieres G, Bogdanovich JM, Bozinovic F (2016) Ontogenetic thermal tolerance and performance of ectotherms at variable temperatures.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>