<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on The Biology Reproducibility Project</title>
    <link>/tags/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on The Biology Reproducibility Project</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Copyright 2018 Jeffrey A. Walker</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Data from: Response of bluebunch wheatgrass to invasion differences in competitive ability among invader-experienced and naïve populations</title>
      <link>/post/data-from-response-of-bluebunch-wheatgrass-to-invasion-differences-in-competitive-ability-among-invader-experienced-and-na%C3%AFve-populations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/data-from-response-of-bluebunch-wheatgrass-to-invasion-differences-in-competitive-ability-among-invader-experienced-and-na%C3%AFve-populations/</guid>
      <description>Sources Summary Caveats Setup Import Reproducibility 3.1.1 Seedling  Statistical red flags   Sources Gibson A, Nelson CR, Atwater DZ (2018) Response of bluebunch wheatgrass to invasion: Differences in competitive ability among invader-experienced and invader-naïve populations. Functional Ecology 32(7): 1857-1866. https://doi.org/10.1111/1365-2435.13090
Gibson AL, Nelson CR, Atwater DZ (2018) Data from: Response of bluebunch wheatgrass to invasion: differences in competitive ability among invader-experienced and naïve populations. Dryad Digital Repository.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data from: The significance of prey avoidance behaviour for the maintenance of a predator colour polymorphism</title>
      <link>/post/data-from-the-significance-of-prey-avoidance-behaviour-for-the-maintenance-of-a-predator-colour-polymorphism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/data-from-the-significance-of-prey-avoidance-behaviour-for-the-maintenance-of-a-predator-colour-polymorphism/</guid>
      <description>Sources Summary Caveats Setup Import Reproducibility Experiment 1 Statistical methods cleaning and recoding Table 1 reported table 1 Effect of spider treatments Figure 1  Experiment 2 Statistical Methods Offer 1 – nonparametric 2-way ANOVA Figure 2 Offer 2   Statistical Red Flags   Sources Ajuria Ibarra H, Kinahan M, Marcetteau J, Mehigan AJR, Ziegelmeier RO, Reader T (2018) The significance of prey avoidance behaviour for the maintenance of a predator colour polymorphism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data from Organic matter and nutrient inputs from large wildlife influence ecosystem function in the Mara River, Africa</title>
      <link>/post/data-from-organic-matter-and-nutrient-inputs-from-large-wildlife-influence-ecosystem-function-in-the-mara-river-africa/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/data-from-organic-matter-and-nutrient-inputs-from-large-wildlife-influence-ecosystem-function-in-the-mara-river-africa/</guid>
      <description>Sources Summary Caveats Set up Import Reproducibility Nutrient dissolution rates Statistical methods ANOVA results Posthoc pairwise comparisons  Decomposition rates Statistical methods ANOVA results  Nutrient limitation Statistical method Respiration Results Chlorophyll a results  Ecosystem Function Experimental Streams River Biofilms    Statistical red-flags   Sources Subalusky AL, Dutton CL, Njoroge L, Rosi EJ, Post DM (2018) Organic matter and nutrient inputs from large wildlife influence ecosystem function in the Mara River, Africa.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data from: Density-dependent positive feedbacks buffer aquatic plants from interactive effects of eutrophication and predator loss</title>
      <link>/post/data-from-density-dependent-positive-feedbacks-buffer-aquatic-plants-from-interactive-effects-of-eutrophication-and-predator-loss/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/data-from-density-dependent-positive-feedbacks-buffer-aquatic-plants-from-interactive-effects-of-eutrophication-and-predator-loss/</guid>
      <description>Sources Summary Caveats Set up Import data cleaning  Reproducibility Appendix S5 Table S1 reproducing epiphytic algae biomass columns  in-text Appendix S5 Table S2 Figure 2  Statistical Red-flags Figure red-flags  Simulate this   Sources Source: Donadi S, Austin ÅN, Svartgren E, Eriksson BK, Hansen JP, Eklöf JS (2018) Density-dependent positive feedbacks buffer aquatic plants from interactive effects of eutrophication and predator loss. Ecology 99(11): 2515-2524.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data from: Litter removal in a tropical rain forest reduces fine root biomass and production but litter addition has few effects</title>
      <link>/post/data-from-litter-removal-in-a-tropical-rain-forest-reduces-fine-root-biomass-and-production-but-litter-addition-has-few-effects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/data-from-litter-removal-in-a-tropical-rain-forest-reduces-fine-root-biomass-and-production-but-litter-addition-has-few-effects/</guid>
      <description>Sources Summary Caveats Set up Functions  import Note in file Data inconsistencies Data pre-processing  Reproducibility Section: Fine root mass and production My ANOVA results reported ANOVA results Did the authors use a one way ANOVA with no random effects? Figure 1 post-hoc tests for fig 1 Fine root mass production effects of treatment on FRB and FRB production figure 2  Section: Fine root length: standing crop, production and survivorship table 1 Figure 3 post hoc tests for fig.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data from: Interactions among predators and plant specificity protects herbivores from top predators</title>
      <link>/post/data-from-interactions-among-predators-and-plant-specificity-protects-herbivores-from-top-predators/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/data-from-interactions-among-predators-and-plant-specificity-protects-herbivores-from-top-predators/</guid>
      <description>Summary Caveats Set up Import Reproducibility Effect on total predators my results reported results  Effect on total herbaceous my results reported results  ANOVA table in Appendix 3, Table S1 Fig 1 Subsetting the response spiders predatory insects Hemiptera Coleoptera Lepidoptera Orthoptera  Fig S6  Statistical red-flags   Source: Bosc C, Roets F, Hui C, Pauw A (2018) Interactions among predators and plant specificity protect herbivores from top predators.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>