<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Experiment on The Biology Reproducibility Project</title>
    <link>/tags/experiment/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Experiment on The Biology Reproducibility Project</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Copyright 2018 Jeffrey A. Walker</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/experiment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Data from Ontogenetic thermal tolerance and performance of ectotherms at variable temperatures</title>
      <link>/post/data-from-ontogenetic-thermal-tolerance-and-performance-of-ectotherms-at-variable-temperatures/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/data-from-ontogenetic-thermal-tolerance-and-performance-of-ectotherms-at-variable-temperatures/</guid>
      <description>Background Summary of reproducibility Reproducibility Table 1 Table 2 Table 3 Figure 2  Post-publication review Use the full model to compare to Huey &amp;amp; Kinsolver Shift in UTL  Red Flags   Background Explored changes in thermal performance curve in response to rearing at 1 of 4 temperature classes (2 mean temperatures x 2 temperature fluctations). Compared to Huey &amp;amp; Kingsolver’s three evolutionary responses, so considered this an ontogenetic response.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data from: Success despite the stress -- violet-green swallows increase glucocorticoids and maintain reproductive output despite experimental increases in flight costs</title>
      <link>/post/data-from-success-despite-the-stress-violet-green-swallows-increase-glucocorticoids-and-maintain-reproductive-output-despite-experimental-increases-in-flight-costs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/data-from-success-despite-the-stress-violet-green-swallows-increase-glucocorticoids-and-maintain-reproductive-output-despite-experimental-increases-in-flight-costs/</guid>
      <description>Sources Rivers JW, Newberry GN, Schwarz CJ, Ardia DR (2017) Success despite the stress: violet-green swallows increase glucocorticoids and maintain reproductive output despite experimental increases in flight costs. Functional Ecology 31(1): 235-244. https://doi.org/10.1111/1365-2435.12719 [Google Scholar]
Data source: https://datadryad.org/resource/doi:10.5061/dryad.3bc3s
 Background xxx
 Data fn &amp;lt;- &amp;#39;RiversetalVGSWhandicappingRawData.xls&amp;#39; file_path &amp;lt;- paste(base_path, folder, fn, sep=&amp;#39;/&amp;#39;) bird &amp;lt;- data.table(read_excel(file_path, sheet = &amp;#39;Tab3 &amp;quot;a8&amp;quot;&amp;#39;)) bird[, Treatment:=factor(Treatment)] bird[, Capture_Period:=factor(Nestling_Age)] bird_wide &amp;lt;- dcast(bird, Year + Treatment + BandNo + DOY_Initiation + day3mass ~ Capture_Period, value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data from: Density triggers maternal hormones that increase adaptive offspring growth in a wild mammal</title>
      <link>/post/data-from-density-triggers-maternal-hormones-that-increase-adaptive-offspring-growth-in-a-wild-mammal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/data-from-density-triggers-maternal-hormones-that-increase-adaptive-offspring-growth-in-a-wild-mammal/</guid>
      <description>Sources Background Reproducibility Effect of spruce cone availability on local density (Fig. 1B) Effect of Density on growth rate (Fig. 2/Table S2) Effect of Density on fecal cortisol metabolites (Fig. 3/Table S4) Effect of FCM on offspring growth rate (Table S5) Effect of experiment Cortisol on growth rate (Table S6)  Red flags Effect of Density on growth rate (Fig. 2/Table S2) Growth rate is a change score and is confounding by the basline Figure 2 doesn’t make sense  Effect of Density on fecal cortisol metabolites (Fig.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>