<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Anova on The Biology Reproducibility Project</title>
    <link>/tags/anova/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Anova on The Biology Reproducibility Project</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Copyright 2018 Jeffrey A. Walker</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/anova/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Data from: Response of bluebunch wheatgrass to invasion differences in competitive ability among invader-experienced and naïve populations</title>
      <link>/post/data-from-response-of-bluebunch-wheatgrass-to-invasion-differences-in-competitive-ability-among-invader-experienced-and-na%C3%AFve-populations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/data-from-response-of-bluebunch-wheatgrass-to-invasion-differences-in-competitive-ability-among-invader-experienced-and-na%C3%AFve-populations/</guid>
      <description>Sources Summary Caveats Setup Import Reproducibility 3.1.1 Seedling Table 1 Figure 1   Statistical red flags   Sources Gibson A, Nelson CR, Atwater DZ (2018) Response of bluebunch wheatgrass to invasion: Differences in competitive ability among invader-experienced and invader-naïve populations. Functional Ecology 32(7): 1857-1866. https://doi.org/10.1111/1365-2435.13090
Gibson AL, Nelson CR, Atwater DZ (2018) Data from: Response of bluebunch wheatgrass to invasion: differences in competitive ability among invader-experienced and naïve populations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data from: Habitat management alters thermal opportunity</title>
      <link>/post/data-from-habitat-management-alters-thermal-opportunity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/data-from-habitat-management-alters-thermal-opportunity/</guid>
      <description>Sources Summary Caveats Setup Import Cleaning Reproducibility Selected temperatures and thermal quality of habitat Thermal preference (Tset) Thermal quality of habitat (de) Table 1 Encounter rates Fig 2  Lizard body temperatures and extent of thermoregulation Thermal performance curves and critical thermal limits  Statistical Red Flags Best practice recommendations   Sources Neel LK, McBrayer LD (2018) Habitat management alters thermal opportunity. Functional Ecology 32(8): 2029-2039. https://doi.org/10.1111/1365-2435.13123</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data from Critical thermal limits affected differently by developmental and adult thermal fluctuations</title>
      <link>/post/data-from-critical-thermal-limits-affected-differently-by-developmental-and-adult-thermal-fluctuations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/data-from-critical-thermal-limits-affected-differently-by-developmental-and-adult-thermal-fluctuations/</guid>
      <description>Sources Background Reproducibility key Caveats  Reproducibility Table 1 (Results of ANOVA for effects on CTmin and CTmax of ±4 and ±8°C amplitude fluctuation after developmental acclimation (Fig. 2A)) Table 2 results Table 3 results  Post-publication review   Sources Salachan PV, Sørensen JG (2017) Critical thermal limits affected differently by developmental and adult thermal fluctuations. Journal of Experimental Biology 220(23): 4471-4478. https://doi.org/10.1242/jeb.165308
Salachan PV, Sørensen JG (2017) Data from: Critical thermal limits affected differently by developmental and adult thermal fluctuations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data from The interaction between predation risk and food ration on behavior and morphology of Eurasian perch</title>
      <link>/post/data-from-the-interaction-between-predation-risk-and-food-ration-on-behavior-and-morphology-of-eurasian-perch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/data-from-the-interaction-between-predation-risk-and-food-ration-on-behavior-and-morphology-of-eurasian-perch/</guid>
      <description>Sources Background Reproducibility key Caveats  Reproducibility Figure 1/Table 1 (Condition and Length) Condition index Table 1 Tukey Contrasts  Figure 2/Table 2 (Behavior) Table 2  Morphometrics  Post-publication review   Sources Svanbäck R, Zha Y, Brönmark C, Johansson F (2017) The interaction between predation risk and food ration on behavior and morphology of Eurasian perch. Ecology and Evolution 7(20): 8567-8577. https://doi.org/10.1002/ece3.3330
Svanback R, Zha Y, Brönmark C, Johansson F (2017) Data from: The interaction between predation risk and food ration on behavior and morphology of Eurasian perch.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>