<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Anova on The Biology Reproducibility Project</title>
    <link>/tags/anova/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Anova on The Biology Reproducibility Project</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Copyright 2018 Jeffrey A. Walker</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/anova/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Data from Critical thermal limits affected differently by developmental and adult thermal fluctuations</title>
      <link>/post/data-from-critical-thermal-limits-affected-differently-by-developmental-and-adult-thermal-fluctuations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/data-from-critical-thermal-limits-affected-differently-by-developmental-and-adult-thermal-fluctuations/</guid>
      <description>Sources Background Reproducibility key Caveats  Reproducibility Table 1 (Results of ANOVA for effects on CTmin and CTmax of ±4 and ±8°C amplitude fluctuation after developmental acclimation (Fig. 2A)) Table 2 results Table 3 results  Post-publication review   Sources Salachan PV, Sørensen JG (2017) Critical thermal limits affected differently by developmental and adult thermal fluctuations. Journal of Experimental Biology 220(23): 4471-4478. https://doi.org/10.1242/jeb.165308
Salachan PV, Sørensen JG (2017) Data from: Critical thermal limits affected differently by developmental and adult thermal fluctuations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data from The interaction between predation risk and food ration on behavior and morphology of Eurasian perch</title>
      <link>/post/data-from-the-interaction-between-predation-risk-and-food-ration-on-behavior-and-morphology-of-eurasian-perch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/data-from-the-interaction-between-predation-risk-and-food-ration-on-behavior-and-morphology-of-eurasian-perch/</guid>
      <description>Sources Background Reproducibility key Caveats  Reproducibility Figure 1/Table 1 (Condition and Length) Condition index Table 1 Tukey Contrasts  Figure 2/Table 2 (Behavior) Table 2  Morphometrics  Post-publication review   Sources Svanbäck R, Zha Y, Brönmark C, Johansson F (2017) The interaction between predation risk and food ration on behavior and morphology of Eurasian perch. Ecology and Evolution 7(20): 8567-8577. https://doi.org/10.1002/ece3.3330
Svanback R, Zha Y, Brönmark C, Johansson F (2017) Data from: The interaction between predation risk and food ration on behavior and morphology of Eurasian perch.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>